Some people just can't get it to ring.
They won't turn it on.
When I was a kid, they told me not to blow it in the middle of the night.
He said snakes were coming.
My dad was blowing so hard.
I tried not to imitate him, but then I couldn't blow anymore.
Maybe it was a curse.
Whistles are usually blown in places like this, like at work.
It's said that it's a thing that doesn't blow well.
You blow your mouth when you're walking down the street.
It's hard to find people who blow their mouths when they're walking around.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to welcome you again today for a live broadcast.
It's been a long time.
It's been a while.
I'm glad to hear that you haven't lost your hair.
Suddenly, after the summer break, my hair turns blonde and it's all messed up.
That's right, after the vacations.
It'll be fun when that happens.
That's true.
With that in mind, I'd like to start recording right away.
I look forward to working with you again this week.
Thank you very much.
Yes, that's all I have to say.
There are many restaurants and eateries in the world.
And there are colors that stimulate the appetite, right?
Appetizing colors?
For example, there are many ramen shops... that use red.
Yes, red.
Yellow and other such colors are often used in restaurant signboards.
On the other hand, blue...
Blue or green...
Green is a color that's used in some restaurants, but sometimes it's a little too bold, and it's not as if it suddenly makes you lose your appetite.
It's not that I suddenly lose my appetite, but red and yellow are more appetizing, aren't they?
The other day, I came across an unexpected thing at a movie theater.
There was a blue hot dog in the theater.
This is a picture of it...
It's a bit strange to see it, don't you think?
It's blue because of Yokohama, but anyway, it looks a little unappetizing.
But when I tried it, it was delicious!
Good evening!
Look at this!
What is it?
Blue hot dog!
Wow....
What is it?
Amazing!
But you know what, when I ate it, it was delicious.
What? A regular hot dog?
Just a regular hot dog.
Wow!
You put red ketchup on it?
Yes, yes, red and yellow.
After all, if you put red and yellow on it, it will be very colorful...
That's right.
A while ago.
What's good?
It has three colors.
It's a bit of a surprise at first.
A little bit.
It's...
It's even bluer than the picture, but it's a little darker in person.
I wish they would do this kind of thing more and more.
Now then, let's get right to it.
Well, let's get on with it... this week is jam-packed with a lot of things, so...
We have to hurry! Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
We have to do it quickly.
Quickly, quickly.
This is taking a long time.
It's taking a long time.
It's a lot of work.
By the way...
Anyway, we've received a lot of letters.
Let's see, which one is it?
Let's see...
Uh...
First of all, I'd like to show you an interesting picture.
Shall we take a look at an interesting picture first to get the momentum going?
Let's do that.
I'm Mr. Kitakubu, Tokyo.
Thank you very much.
His drawings are very original.
He's got a big head.
He sends us these kind of pictures that look kind of creepy-cute.
It's very unique.
It's like this.
Wait a minute.
Let's see...
Let's see... Yes.
This is him.
Oh, this is him.
Yeah, this is the guy.
Oh, my God.
The other day, you know...
There's a mountain pass in Kanagawa called Yabitsu Pass.
He sang about riding there on a bicycle.
He drew a picture of it
and he made a picture of it....
That's great!
I'm a little bit happy, but it's kind of
It's very unique.
You're right...
Mario and Luigi were wearing something like kimonos, weren't they?
Yes, they did.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
You're good at deformation.
Yes, you are.
It's really good.
It's like a giant corn.
I don't know where to begin and end with the face.
I want to be like this.
I want to end up like this.
I want to look like a young corn.
Yes, yes, yes.
Well, if it's like this, they could put a camera on the top of my head...
I'm sure you're right, it's really cool.
It's great. It's really great for a TV guy.
I think it will be good for a lot of things.
I'm going to put a lot of hyaluronic acid in here.
And it will look like this? Isn't hyaluronic acid amazing?
That's so bad.
Yes, yes, yes.
That's why I said yes.
Well, let's just say... This corn is a living thing.
Isn't it a living thing?
It's alive.
So, I'd like to try my hand at creating a living thing.
I'd like to try it.
I got this.
There you are, from Kanagawa Ward, Yokohama City.
Thank you very much.
Good evening, Master, Swapon, Ebitu, and staff!
I have sent you an e-mail to contribute to the “Creative Creatures” section.
May I submit a subject for the creatures?
Socialist Taori
The Socialist Taori
The Socialist Taori.
It's Japanese.
Socialist?
Socialist Taori.
Taori.
Which one are you?
Taori, you're a socialist.
You're a socialist.
Taoli, you're a socialist.
Taori...
Social flag fold.
Social Flag Fold
One of these days.
No, no, no, no.
I don't know what the hell it is or isn't.
Yes, I do.
Social flag fold.
I've never heard of it, by the way.
Oh.
You're not familiar with it?
No.
No?
I mean...
Well, now that you mention it...
I looked up the correct answer and drew a picture of it. Then I thought of it for the first time, and it occurred to me that I've rarely seen this creature in TV specials.
I've rarely seen this creature on TV.
Yes...
Oh, well...
What's socialist about it?
You'd never guess from the name.
It's a bit like “Socialist Alley.
Your pen's been talking again. Yes, it has.
It's going, it's going, it's going, it's going.
Socialist. That's about right.
Yes, sir.
Socialist
May I?
Yes, sir.
Oh, no.
Now, we're talking about social flag weaving.
Yes, sir.
Well, first of all, let's start with the teacher, shall we?
Yes, I'm on it.
Sensei, yes.
Social flag weaving.
Bang.
Oh!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. You're kind of good.
Oh, okay.
Mm-hmm.
It's like you're always kind of reasonable or something.
Mm-hm.
Yeah. - Yeah.
It's probably just a bug, right? Yes, it is. Bugs, yes.
You have those flags, right? Yes, that's right.
Like this, it's like... Yes, it is. It's a flag weaver,
I thought it might be an insect that is shaped to weave a flag,
It's a praying mantis.
Mantis? Suddenly I got scared.
It's a praying mantis. It's like a member of the praying mantis family.
Not a praying mantis, but a praying mantis. A praying mantis is that one? Yes, it is.
What? No, no, if you're doing it that way, please write it like this. This is the flag. That's right.
This is a large and developed praying mantis. Oh, I see, I see. That's how it is.
No, no, no, well, but it's something.
I feel a little growth. That's right. Even you, Mr. Mayama, compared to those days, how do you feel? I mean, how do you compare to those days? Mayama-san. I had a vague fear, you know? Yes, that's right. I don't know.
I used to have little screams every time.
No more screams.
I was scared.
It's like a human being wrote something.
I can see traces of it.
It's like humans wrote something.
It's important to keep writing.
I'll prove it.
I've said it before... my idea of society... Hatanori, here.
Bird!
The crane in “The Crane Returns” weaves “Hatakeori.” Oh, weaves... I see.
What's so socialist about a bird that looks like it's going to weave in the fields?
What's socialist about it?
I have this image of news commentators with the pattern of a hair parted into 7 thirds.
Like that pattern.
That's socialist, isn't it?
Socialist
He makes socialist comments.
I'm more of a socialist.
Socialist
I see.
But maybe he's perceptive.
I thought it might be a bird with that kind of pattern.
Bird.
Insect
Insects.
Yes.
Close, close, or in the sense of a bird, correct.
So, the social flag weaver is a kind of sparrow.
This sparrow is a kind of sparrow.
This sparrow looks like a sparrow in Africa.
What's amazing is that birds basically build nests.
Birds build nests, but they are usually small and compact.
This social weaver forms a huge colony!
Social skin
Hundreds of birds live together in a colony.
They build a house by themselves.
So it's like what we call “Tower Man” now.
There's probably some kind of management association.
They do maintenance on a regular basis.
I wonder if that has something to do with society.
Bird society.
I don't know...
I'm a teacher.
There are birds like that?
Is this the whole nest?
This is a normal tree, right?
This is a tree.
You mean the size of a tree?
This is the size of a tree.
This is the size of a bird.
It's big!
Oh, my God!
Eeeeeeeeee! Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee! ee
개毛라고 Hope you enjoy it, don't you?
Well, it's necessary to live, and you don't do anything more or less than that.
I really respect you, but every time I hear something like this, it's like I'm trying to be popular or something.
But do you think animals want to be popular too?
Males do, don't they?
So let's hear another letter...
Let's see...
Thank you, Mr. Shirokane from Shibuya Ward, Tokyo.
You're a Mayan enthusiast by profession.
Thank you very much.
She often compares us to cats and sends us very cute letters.
There was an incident on the show the other day.
Last week, Mariko was on shift.
I was...
You know...
I went on location with him this summer, and when we were leaving...
After we broke up, on the way home...
I said, “Mariko, you're a beautiful girl, aren't you?
I told him that I remembered it.
Then he said he was embarrassed.
She said she was embarrassed.
The Mariko Bishojo Incident.
My Mariko Bishojo.
That's right.
I got a lot of feedback from people.
She even drew a picture for Shiroko!
The other day, at the Kannai Devil's live broadcast.
Wasser told Mariko
Sarpon called Mariko a beautiful girl.
It's true.
I drew that scene in the style of a school play.
It's summer.
Who are the characters in this storyline?
A noisy boy in my class.
Me
Shy boy
Sarpon
Blonde best friend, golden ready-made dumpling buns
The girl who likes to gossip, the teacher
day-doctor who pretends to erase the blackboard and looks at it.
It's so real.
May I?
It's like this.
Sapan says Marika's a pretty girl.
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
I can't believe I'm listening to you.
I'm like, “Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What a nice school.
It's nice.
This school sounds fun.
I want you to come by and deliver some prints, too.
I want...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
That was embarrassing.
That was really embarrassing.
Well, well, well, well.
That's all I have to say.
And also...
A moment ago...
A creature.
Sparrowhawks.
Oh, well...
I don't think we haven't seen many sparrows in Japan recently.
I thought it was strange that they were hiding somewhere because of the heat wave, but I thought it would be better if I sent you a letter.
I was wondering if they were hiding somewhere because of the heat wave, as usual, or something, but then someone sent me that letter.
Master Mukogawa-san! Very cool! Thank you!
Beyond the period.
Like Beyond the Period.
Master Nakajima!
Hey, Ebichu! Good-bye, Bill!
Komban-ne-biru!
I know this is sudden, but have you seen any sparrows in town?
Actually, the number of sparrows has been decreasing rapidly in the last few years.
They've been listed as an endangered species.
I see.
Well, I hadn't seen any lately.
I felt their keen eyes on me
I took a picture of it.
So I decided to take a picture of it.
Photo sparrow
It's a sparrow, isn't it?
So cute!
Isn't it?
Sparrows!
Sparrows are so alert.
What's wrong with them?
It's not endangered, but...
But the Ministry of the Environment says it's endangered, so it's endangered.
Yes, it is.
Why?
No, no, no, no, no, no...
The ecosystem has changed.
Anybody sad?
Wow, look who's here.
Seriously, who knows about this?
I don't think so.
Is there anyone from the Ministry of the Environment?
Why not?
Why?
Why Jun?
Jun.
It's about time.
You scared me.
I thought it was someone's name.
No.
I don't know why. But then again, some people don't know.
It's a tough business, isn't it? Animal society too.
Whenever there's an increase in the number of animals, they're suddenly called vermin.
Deer are in trouble because there are too many of them, and they're protected to some extent.
They've been protected in the mountains.
Recently, people don't use guns anymore.
So they've been left to fend for themselves.
And they're eating all the leaves.
And they eat a lot of leaves.
I heard that deer basically eat a lot.
In no time at all, the mountain became like a bald mountain.
Landslides could happen there.
There are stories about what to do about the landslides... it's tough to protect them... it's tough.
The first is that there's less food for the farmers, and the second is that there's less forest in the area because the land has been cleaned up.
That's probably why they're slowly and gradually coming out, and they say it's due to the lack of food, such as the decrease in rice paddies.
In the old days, they used to put grains of rice here in the garden, and set up a colander like this with a stick.
Then we attached a string like this, and when the sparrows came in, we would peg them off.
They don't go in so fast, because they're strong at cutting back
That's why, you know, look at it like this, isn't this a device?
If you pull this stick with this, we'll get caught. It's like...
It's like, “Oh, they're coming to get me!
He's so smart.
It's like, “Oh, here it comes.
He's like, “Oh, here it comes,” and then he's like, “Oh, no, I'm not going to get caught.
He's so wonderful.
I can't remember the last time I did it.
But it was so amazing... we were doing it for two or three hours.
You know, you're hooked.
You catch them, right?
What are you going to do when you catch him?
I'll catch him and talk to him.
You know...
I've had grilled sparrow chicken before.
Is there such a thing?
I'm sorry Suzu-chan.
I'm sorry Suzu, but there are many people who have never been able to catch a sparrow that way.
And yet, there are comic books about it.
I thought it was easy to catch them too.
They must be really careful.
He must be really smart, basically.
They're really quick.
He's quick... in a split second.
Well, well, well, well, well...
So that's how today went.
It all happened so fast...
This week has flown by in the blink of an eye.
How is everyone doing?
By the way, on a side note...
I heard that Chuo was very good.
Why didn't you come?
Please invite me.
I'm the one who's going.
It's a little too zoozy.
That was awesome!
It was fun.
Well then...
I was very impressed to see a new stage of Ebitu, a little different from the previous one!
It was a live performance with a band, no dancing.
The audience and fans were seated without psyllium, so they could enjoy the music in a pure state.
It was so much fun to enjoy the music in a pure state!
It was so great!
Thank you so much!
There are still some factors left to be taken care of.
Chichibu is a great place.
It's in Chichibu.
Muse Park?
That's right.
It's in the mountains.
There.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. There's no signal.
I see.
There's no signal at all.
If we reharter for a day and don't touch our cell phones for two days...
It's like a digital detox.
Oh, that's nice.
It's nice.
And the new costumes were so cute.
Pink.
Chichibu...
I've said it many, many times.
It's funny.
Well, you see...
There are many famous gourmet restaurants, but it's a land with a kind of god-like atmosphere.
It's like if Japan went in a different direction from what it is now, it would be like that.
It's a little bit like an interesting time slip.
A time slip.
I see.
It makes me a little nervous.
The streets...
It's like the Showa period.
I don't know how to say it.
It's just... it's so nice.
It has a unique feeling.
But Devil's...
I'm sure you all enjoyed it.
I've been here so much!
There's so much good food.
Soba (buckwheat noodles), for example.
Soba is great!
Governor's soba is the best!
Yes, it is!
Waraji katsudon...
Yo!
Waraji katsudon!
That room is amazing.
Mr. M. Nagaoka...
It was nice.
Devil's Charge.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry, I don't have great reception, so it's hard to see the mobile ticket screen, but it's hard to see the electronic ticket.
I wonder what's up with that... do you have to open it in advance?
I've been keeping it in my pocket for a long time.
I'm going to take it with me.
I see.
I don't have to worry about it at all, but the general public does.
I don't use it that much.
I could do without it if I wanted to.
You talk on line once in a while, don't you?
Once in a while.
Maybe once every six months.
Yes, you do.
I'm the god in the center.
I got a debut charge.
It's a little bit...
There are a lot of shrines in the spiritual sphere, aren't there?
Yes, there are.
Like Shichibu Shrine...
Mimine Shrine...
There's a very famous shrine.
It's a very interesting place with an atmosphere
It's a very interesting place with such an atmosphere.
The festivals are very unique.
Various festivals.
They shoot rocket fireworks.
They say, “Sha, sha, sha, sha!
The moon is very interesting.
It's been a while since I've been there.
The leaves will change colors this season.
And there's a hot spring.
Well, well, well...
Well, I guess that's about it for today's live broadcast.
I see. So next week we'll be live, and the week after that?
No, the week after that.
I'm sorry, I'm going to have to take next week off.
I'm sorry, I'm not allowed to say anything about that. About the broadcast?
I'm not going to tell you.
It's just... It's a very serious matter.
There it is! There it is!
It's a big deal.
There are unavoidable circumstances.
Circumstances that cannot be excused.
Actually, I have a miraculously open schedule for the next week or two.
I have a miraculously open schedule for the next week or two.
So, if you guys request TO THE SKY or something, I'll be there as much as I can.
I'll be there as much as I can.
So please send me your requests as soon as you can.
Then, let's go to Chichibu or something.
Oh, okay, I'll go there.
That's so cool!
Let's go to La Vue.
Oh, I love it.
Get on the La Vue...
I wanna go.
“Wow, it's yellow. It's yellow.
Yellow, yellow, yellow, yellow...
If you have any requests, we would be happy to respond to them as soon as we have time.
I'll be off next week, so I guess the week after next for the live broadcast.
Thank you very much for your time today.
Subtitles by Ishinokami